Fraser Alexander Wardrope

Curriculum Vitae

DOB 20.06.1985

18 Whittle Road

Ayr

KA8 9PY

Mobile 07894607584

Email: fraser.wardrope@gmail.com

PERSONAL PROFILE

I am looking for a sales or customer service based role as I have always been able to build a rapport when dealing with customers, complaints, issues and renewals/contracts. I am able to sell any product or service using my experience and ability to build an immediate rapport with my clients and establish their needs specific to them through tried and tested sales procedures. I also have a vast experience in dealing with customer service issues and I would always go the extra mile for my clients when possible to improve chances of repeat business. I am an experienced and self-motivated individual with a width of knowledge in a sales environment. I have over 10 years experience within the call centre industry in various roles, I have a vast knowledge of inbound and outbound sales and customer service requirements. I consider myself to have the ability to carry out any role that is put in front of me and I pride myself on having a wealth of knowledge on finding a customer's needs, finding the best option for my client and making sure they get the best deal for them.

SKILLS & ATTRIBUTES

Excellent communication, presentation & organisational skills

Work well on my own initiative and within a team

Considerate and proactive

Enjoy new challenges

Learn new skills quickly and effectively

Complete all tasks to a high standard

Dependable & reliable

Work well under pressure

Hard working and enthusiastic

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Arringo Ltd

July 2018 - December 2019

I started working for Arringo 2 weeks after moving to Malta. I have been part of the customer service payments team since I started. My main tasks include approving client withdrawals, checking for potential fraudulent activity, speeding up client deposits by checking for any issues and solving them when possible. Calling clients when they have issues or to approve large withdrawals and also conversing with clients by email or on live chat. I also, now, train new agents when they join the team. Although I enjoyed working here, I don't feel it quite challenged me enough, I know the challenges involved in sales and it makes me push that extra mile to achieve my personal goals, which are always higher than any targets given to me. I decided to leave Malta and come back home in December 2019.

Training Plus Ltd, Account Manager/Sales February 2018 - June 2018

I worked here for a short period before deciding to move to Malta. I sold training programmes to businesses and managed accounts for clients. The programmes ranged from health and safety through to more specialised courses such as IPAF Dual training and forklift counterbalance etc. I also managed new and current customer accounts, keeping up to date with renewals and booking in any training required. I dealt with web enquiries and a lot of customers contact through email as well as on the phone. In my first month I brought in more revenue than anyone ever did in their first month. I was also the only agent ever to hit target in every month there.

Utility Solutions Direct Ltd, Sales Director / Utility Broker, March 2017- January 2018

I joined this call centre cold calling business clients on a dialler system where I built rapport, collected contract information, offered alternatives and sold contracts, which usually had to be started on a specific start date. I dealt with all types of electricity meters from standard 01, 02 meters which are usually household meters to max demand and half hourly meters.

The clients I sold varied dependent on products as below:

Mobile phones - EE & O2

Electricity & Gas- Eon, Scottish Power, SSE, British Gas, EDF, Opus, Dual Energy, Yu Energy, CNG, Clear Business Utilities, Utilita & Gazprom .

Telecoms & Broadband - Talktalk, Clear Business Telecoms & XLN

Water - Clear Business Water & Everflow

1 Call Direct Ltd, Residential and Business Sales Executive, September 2012 - March 2017 (Various Campaigns)

To deliver outstanding performance in a sales environment. I continually met and exceeded my targets.

September 2012-March 2015 - Scottish Power Residential Outbound - Cold calling customers to give them better deals on their electricity and gas supplies for their home energy. I realise that price is not always the forefront of customers minds. I always look for alternatives when hit with objections. I always feel my objection handling is a very strong part of my sales pitch.

March 2015-January 2017 - Scottish Power Business Outbound - Calling existing and new clients to add additional sites or to offer better deals going forward. I was very successful in this role as I was in any other sales role with Scottish power. I feel my straight talking and no nonsense attitude really helped me win my clients over in this position.

June 2013-January 2014- Scottish Power Change of Tenancy - I was asked, during my time on the residential sales team, if I could help out, in a more customer service type role. Scottish Powers customer service had been heavily under fire. I saw this as a bit of a challenge and was only too willing to give it a go. I felt this would help develop my skills, when handling complaints and also resolving many different issues customers were having.

Gr8 Works/Gr8 Enterprise/Call Centre Sales February 2007-August 2012

I worked for Scottish Power in this role, however here it was on the residential campaign. I also have team management, account management and coaching experience in my time throughout these business'. This campaign was always the main bread winner for the company, which changed hands twice during my time there. I was kept on, when many others were made redundant. I sold electricity, gas, dual fuel and also boiler cover tariff's to households during my time here.

October 2001-January 2007

During these years I worked various jobs from sales staff, part time whilst still at school, to construction work for Barr Ltd. In all my roles, during work, I've always dealt with customers, whether face to face, or on the phone.

QUALIFICATIONS

Mathematics - Higher C

Chemistry - Higher C

Mathematics - S. Grade 1

Graphics - S. Grade 1

Chemistry - S. Grade 1

Craft & Design - S. Grade 1

Biology - S. Grade 1

French - S. Grade 2

English - S. Grade 3

INTERESTS & ACTIVITIES

I've recently rejoined the gym I was a member of before moving abroad. I previously was a member of a local pub darts team, so I plan to start practicing again and can hopefully get myself good enough to rejoin my old team mates.

REFERENCE

Available On Request